but called over to the regular scale to me in my city council Monday April 15th, 2024 that I have two public input and it's good to personal chances we have nine for three times less.
I have a question under the on the claims list under risk management.
There's a $10,000 deduct for a legit bodily injury. Can we talk about that?
I tripped in the street.
Mark was brought, brought sent and brought it up to us.
Oh, that makes sense. The first question I had was what was the issue? The second one I had was why was it a perfect even amount?
If we did we like, like, pay somebody off not, that's the wrong word to use, but you know what I'm saying?
Did we settle? Did we settle with somebody? So it was deductible.
Jennifer, did you have some data for your home?
I don't necessarily need to see it. I just don't know what it looks for.
I felt like there's an important enough amount that maybe we should question.
All right, I'm good. I'll just try to prove claims.
Say good.
Thank you.
Okay.
Four minutes from the Mark 25th, 2020, for a regular need.
Motion proof.
Thank you.
Hi.
Your aye.
Five.
Or?
Or, FQ2426 certificate in deposit agreement for one million seventeen,
or fourteen dollars three hundred and seventeen thousand thirty and seventeen five out of fifty cents per
and we saw it out for local financial institutions.
We received three beds, one no bid.
The prices that came in was 35,000 roughly to 88,000.
And first national bank came in with our things at 35,144, our best came in at 8,9,4,30, and security bank and trust came in with the highest, they were offering a 5.13% and it came in at 87,891 to security banks.
Any questions?
Hi.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
Thanks.
Increase the municipal pool of admission fees and the bad, and Kimberly.
Pool admission fees, so that we're more in line with surrounding area pools.
We have had the same pool admission fees for over 10 years.
And what we'd like to do is put up for live and under.
They can be free with the paid adults, and for our patrons that are 6 years of age, through adult, $5.
And then we will have a designated day where all ages can come to the pool for a dollar.
We'd also like to change our prices on the pool parties a little bit and explain what they need to do there.
But with our pool parties, we've brought them all the way in at the except for you to see our after hours.
I came to you guys.
We've put all those in the pool parties.
We have the ability to run 6 parties a day.
I think it's going to be because the kids will be there.
Not only after hours, we've grown.
Anybody to play with?
Obviously we're going to offer after hours for the interest in them.
We'll need to staff them.
What's the latest like you would do?
Obviously you don't have lights in the pool, so that's going to be after hours.
Some of those disco pool parties.
We have the ability to do that.
We would offer them.
We had lights in the pool.
You know that would be something that we could offer.
Sure, we only able to offer 23 hours.
Right.
But doing them during business hours, we're going to be able to increase
our revenue being able to allow more.
Awesome.
So, 48.
Last time when you talked to us,
did you kind of have some graphs extrapolating what you expected
increase in revenue loss?
I did.
That's fine.
I can go back and look at it.
No, they're in our packets.
We still have access to them.
I just wanted to make sure.
I thought they were in there, but I wanted to ask.
Then you can see our prices will be in line with.
That's awesome.
And our current rate was.
$3.
So we're going up to $2.
That's not.
And then adults were four.
I didn't you say you're the staffing.
Won't have to pay for their own red cross.
Black card training.
Because of you.
We brought all that in.
I have just.
So that's going to save the kids that do it a lot of money.
They will not have to front that money.
Could you start recruiting for that?
Yeah.
And the age is 16.
So the CPR.
So let's.
They don't have to to pay that up front.
We said that that works.
Black card training.
Okay.
And so did.
Did they pay anything?
Okay.
So it was.
It was 200.
It's in the.
they were basically at guard, but they worked the entire season for us to see
reimburse them back that 200,000,000 out of the city without them.
Therefore, it was hard to get kids to do sure. It was hard for them to bridge that money.
These two bottles are new.
And we did that because we were getting calls from both voice homes, youth homes,
that we didn't have the ability to price them out.
So that's why I was included in two.
And when we came back to, we had a huge debt.
And this is just the step of trying to get that.
Yep, great.
Did you talk about before?
Those are going to be done before the season starts?
Yes.
And I'd like the private to ban things that you showed before.
Does it have a rental in there for those?
Right now, it's just going to be two more.
First, preferably, so that, you know, we're going to have to go back to those.
We're just going to be, of course, got first order.
Think with this, we're going to have to raise it.
It'll be utilized to bigger capacity.
We're hoping we're going to reduce some days.
Trying to make it more enticing.
Obviously less than one full day.
So parents have to warm it off.
It's a pool still losing water somewhere.
I need that for a while.
We've released them a lot of hard. Was that before the liner or after?
I'll make a motion to approve.
Sounds like before you go on this, I just want to let you know.
If you approve this, then we have to do an ordinance that sets it out.
But this gives us the go ahead and get that out.
You guys have an opening day set yet?
We're still going to shoot for that one more day week.
Spice pads are an open day for it.
So do I need to change my motion to when we just set up an ordinance?
No, if you bring it to your job.
Not you can do it to you in an ordinance.
Ashley does it.
That's your job.
And you can throw your flag in the comment below.
Hi.
Thank you.
I'm a seven resolution CC 2020 for National Institute of Labor.
In the Citywide ground.
So to be for the time and I know it's citywide ground.
gaan 724.
So contact my.
My name is record.
Thank you.
I want to sponsor this here.
So we've got so many calls.
Customers service of myself about we use to citywide.
So we picked the first weekend in May because the next weekend
next weekend's Mother's Day when they normally did it, the second weekend, and so when I'm
asking tonight is that you weigh the fee, which is a $5 permit, and I talked to Jennifer,
we make about $200 a year off of it, so it'd be just for those two days, though, the waiver
for the fourth and the fifth.
Most of you prove.
Second.
Williams?
All right.
E7, so full.
Second.
Great.
Contrack with cross-linked instructions for Mama, Result Airport, New Terminal Construction,
and entrance drive improvements.
Not to exceed 2,615,000 bucks.
Yes, thank you man.
Before we get started, I'll have a mat, rank here from Garber, and I wanted him to go through the funding
and break down everything.
I don't think in the past we've been a good job of articulating the different funding sources
and the breakdown of the funding and the amount of the city's matches.
So I ask Matt to go.
I mean, it's also in your packet, but, Mac, did you kind of think of how I've talked about that first?
Sure. There's, um, I believe you have two sheets in your packet. The first one was, um, and then the second sheet is actually, uh, includes, um, a couple of BEMs that will help us, um, um, so, you mean we just start with the second one?
Yeah, it's just got to be just like a mapping of mine.
So, on the, uh, on this, basically high level of start high level, there's three main.
The partners in this particular project, the state is a $1 million.
It's a dollar for dollar mat, so you're the second party, the local match, and then the third portion of this is at the funding.
So, uh, eight through, uh, two, uh, and opportunities there that you all have, um, so, and, uh, the way that the funding is set up, um, I'll, I'll try and find is, I think, the third block at the bottom is the easiest to follow.
So, I'll just jump right to that. The, uh, state match there listed a million dollars.
The second for local, uh, is the $1 million dollar for dollar match. That's their requirement.
Can't use FA funds or anything for that one to one match.
And then, then, in the, uh, third portion now, we can start using NPMBI, also basically the third million dollars is a 10% local match.
It's 90% FA, and 10% so, um, so the community is getting the $3 million building for, for approximately $1.1.2 million dollars.
So, that last third million there is actually a 90 to 10.
So, uh, it's, uh, it's a, it's a kind of amazing, it, it's really a unique opportunity because using the FA funds to tag on to this.
Um, this is not, um, it's not common to be able to use the MP funds and BIL funds to go start a facility like this.
The state initiating this and doing that 2 million, and then the balance using a 9010.
Um, it's, uh, you just, these facilities are 2.5 million without really batting eye to do these anymore.
And, uh, that 9010 to finish it off and get that with the budget is, uh, is a great opportunity.
That funds if we don't use those FA funds, that additional, that basically a third million.
Those are, your, your funds that are in a grant, basically an FA account.
They're going to go to, like, taxiways or runways or just, you know, the routine maintenance that we do.
All right.
So, isn't it?
Isn't it?
Can we actually put it into something?
It's going to begin.
and he just doesn't collect this.
So, in any case, I believe the original,
and I came on with Garper Midfall.
So, a lot of this was handed to me,
but Miner Stang was the original approval
for the community was, I think, 1.2 million,
and it was 2.2 total, 1 million from the state.
It was about 1.2 for the match coming in,
and you're actually still within that budget
that was originally discussed for Miner Stang.
But the match total is one, yeah.
So, in any case,
if you were to say money off this state,
there was, you know, you bring that back down,
or whatnot, it's just putting money back into the FAA
coffer that's going to go into the taxiway, run way things.
So, does that help a little bit,
or are there any kind of questions from the high level funding there?
Council and Prived, a Prived, at 1.1, 2,
and we're coming, 1.2, 1.2, 1.2, 1.2, 1.2, 1.9.
The way we approved it the last time was the contract,
the contracts were 2.6, so they had a contract of the 2.619.
And then the city's funding is still the same,
still under 1.2 started approved.
We just have to bring words to a premium contract,
at 2.619.
What were asked in line?
In the next agenda item, it's for the changeover,
so we're doing two things in house to get down to that number
so we did the negotiating, about 125,000 off by doing stormwater.
So stormwater and dirt work in house to reduce those costs.
And then we did that up to the limit, it was a dollar from our match.
If we were to say any more than it's in our 10%,
it's going to really get a 10% return on that, our investment there.
So we cut down to that far, we're $1,000, $1,225,000.
We'll $1,500.
And then we'll have to be detained to work at a price.
I'll have my little bit, as you say, 100%.
It's three grand estate.
Who's the other two?
I'm sorry.
Who were the other two?
The other two was America and...
Our...
Our state agency, right?
Was this...
Min American Dutch report?
There aren't state agencies.
Um...
I think there's some ties there.
There are, there are airports.
Or it's the same way.
They're actually doing the same thing.
Great.
This is a name, right?
Like a most true proof.
Second.
Second, right?
So, what?
What is it?
My.
I've changed one number.
One was cross on the Russian.
A lot of reasonable airport.
We need to promote construction, interest, driver, for a reduction in the map.
One hundred twenty five thousand four hundred nine five dollars.
Most super.
Second.
We step.
All right.
Sender.
Hi.
Williams.
Thank you.
Thank you, gentlemen.
And now that's approved.
We all have a groundwork here.
Right now.
I heard that so much.
Thank you for moving.
You're invited.
I've seen.
Business amendment number twenty four to ask thirteen five apart.
Very twenty five thousand.
From there.
Over time expense.
And the gentleman to the capital.
Pretty much program.
Time to cover the.
A bit.
Build.
For the brush truck.
And expanding a portion of their donations.
The forty four thousand.
And purchase a huge extraction tool.
Library reimbursing.
A general fund.
Fifteen thousand one hundred twenty four dollars twenty cents.
To cover library salaries.
For the open home of the part of libraries adult online high school.
This will be year twenty three twenty four expenses.
Airport.
Maybe hundred twenty nine thousand one hundred six dollars and twelve cents.
For additional matching funds for the terminal grant.
Bringing the total matching funds for the date to one million.
One hundred twenty nine thousand one hundred six dollars and twelve cents.
The.
It's recorded.
That's exactly what it's for.
It's for four things.
The most important one is the rainy day.
Fund.
is going to transfer another 229,000,000,000,000,000 and 12 cents to the airport for the terminal.
The fire department's getting some extraction tools and they're going to upfit a truck, a new truck, and keep from having a lease payment, which is a good thing.
For the right here, I believe that's extrication.
Extrication.
Oh, yes.
No, you spell it, right?
You're announcing it wrong.
Oh, did I pronounce it?
Do we not get grants from the County for some of the fire stuff?
Do we get some of that as it been used it this year at all I know that I mean was it used for that
Okay, thanks for clarifying
How's that old pre-model that old
You got your flag where's the truck at down the park?
Can we get it done before Christmas this year?
Good answer.
Much to approve
All right, okay, that's what we move on. I'm going to make the council where the one of the items in there was the
Extraction or
Extraction, sorry I cannot say it
So the current one we have is broke down and so we'd like to move forward with purchasing one for each truck
And then bring it back on the next meeting
But like I said we don't have one with the one being broke down so we're just going to make the photo where
That Christmas here to answer
So I think what you're saying is you're going to get two y'all's lives
Extraction tools and
Extracation and we're going to need to approve that later
That'd be correct. Where's making the board aware?
I actually seen that work last week and one of them did kind of grow a little bit
So it's probably a good need. So I think he's why he's asking me this he needs to order this for safety
But he just can't get it on to ask the next meeting
see it. It's going to be already ordered. Right. And we'll be using state bid. We'll
personally not to state bid. So.
All right. Good. Good.
11. Own Anderson Engineering Work Authorization of rate for GoPolx Stadium for boundary
survey and parcel split, not to exceed $6,000,000.
Okay.
All right.
Yeah. So we are asking the council to upgrade the own own.
And so to do a sort of rate to great boundaries.
Splash bad in the cuts with school history.
So the school and and quite some time about us.
We see.
The bill.
That would allow them to be able to do.
For instance, they can.
You're a bond issue to improve the stadium.
They can't do that without.
Either ownership of the property or a long term lease.
In order for us to figure out what property we're actually talking about.
We need to have this survey back.
That would allow them to they want to make that their experience.
Right now we're just in a stalemate.
We can't sell to them without going to a third of the people.
Lisa to them.
But.
You know what exactly.
The high schools the only one that uses that facility.
We still ensure.
We still do all night.
That's all.
We still do everything on the city's.
Don't have.
So what we've tried to do for years is come up with some kind of way where they get.
Utilized funding or something to make improvements to that park.
Then as work.
Long time to try to fund solution.
It's just lease.
We still.
If it's no longer used for a ball field.
We'd work back to us.
But this will allow them to have some bonding capacity to make improvements.
But the reason we need the law split is because we're still trying for grants for that walking trail and things.
We can't just even the whole section because we need that space behind it for that walking trail to tie in the tennis courts.
To the splash pad.
So we just paid for the improvements thus far.
We are.
It goes to least, they'll take on the insurance,
so they'll take on the insurance,
the utilities, and all the group ones.
The school.
Are they going to maintain the grounds too?
The grounds also.
They need to take the inside of the fence,
they take care of all right.
Of course, we need to do this.
Nice and press well.
But today we're just spending money for serving.
We'll talk about this some more, right?
Oh, absolutely.
Yeah, this is just for the loss for that.
The lease agreement, and it's not been brought
before you or anything in that nature.
We're just not going to get a legal description
so we can, so you have an idea already
of what the law's supposed to look like?
Yes.
So who's going to end up on the parking lot?
We will own the entryway, coming into the parking lot,
because that connects to the splash pad bridge,
and they will take from the entryway south.
And we'll take entryway north.
Interway north.
We're upgrade on the out-of-pants, about 30 feet.
Includes the scoreboard, that's the reason we're coming back
in the fans, because the kickers that come off the scoreboard,
we wanted to include those in case they wanted to do any outside
bleachers on the outside fans or anything like that.
They had room.
So 30 feet for the perimeter of the pants all the way around?
Yes.
We're coming at that, that you foresee a bond issue coming for improvements
with the field.
So they're wide in the age of about a bit of improvements.
So right to that part, they should have heard of it.
They're much suited as long as we're owning it.
We're going to have to go on this one, turn away.
The other way, then, for the one in the trail, though,
is to see if it's a little bit slow.
Then we're going to have this one going to be a little bit slow.
There's a little bit of a much less slow amount of walking down there.
I'll take it, but we have to see that a lot, there's not a lot to sell that.
The interspersion of the better is the pitch in front of you first,
where it's going to be a part and foot walk in trail.
Part of the walk can get out of the side of the feet,
and the top of the foot walk.
30 times a hundred breaks, and there's not so much.
That's all on us.
There's no way back on the pitch.
But not as long as we're on the pitch, but we're going to have to go on the pitch.
That's not a way.
We're 16 and five on the pitch, but that's not a way to go there.
Anyway, we're saying that we're on the pitch,
and it's clear that we're going to have to go on the pitch.
We get really fast and then put with us all the instruments and OG and then we get that.
Once they get pass us kickers, it's not cut off.
That's the old.
Thank you sir.
Because, thank you.
You heard express that and go on.
Press like and subscribe.
And we'll subscribe to the online people.
If you press subscribe to the social media and post it on the social media, we'll stay on this side.
We'll stay on this side.
We'll be on the other side.
We'll stay on the other side.
So we got another problem that we've ran real into.
We think we've been on that area for the rest of the time.
Oh, I think this book is the ground.
We have loads of courage.
And we can't waste carbon.
That wants to come on a set of researchers.
Didn't there used to be some back here anyway?
I don't know.
Wouldn't pop Warner play football back here, I think.
I think that's a good idea.
I can't remember, but that's part of...
That press box is still there, correct?
Oh, yeah.
Remember the old pulp Warner?
First one.
That's gone.
That's gone?
Yeah.
That's gone.
Hey, what do you call it pop Warner?
Hey.
I hope we'll look at the top of the chart that we will decide.
That was busy.
I don't know why but I'm going to explain it to you.
Second.
It's that volume.
Third.
ability policy is renewing and we're just here tonight to have you approved the City Manager signature for the policy motion to approve
Okay.
Hi.
Parker.
Thank you.
13.
How do they business?
A baby with the residents posting this agenda?
14.
Staff report.
15 mayor, council, community, announcements.
Everybody keep voting for our mascot.
We're going to win this thing.
I don't know.
If everybody, I'm sure, based on the 177,000 people that voted in the last one.
Every one of you had to do a vote.
Because I think our population is maybe an eighth of that.
We're just winning.
We're dominating.
We're killing it.
We're just going to just come out today and we're already 11,000 votes ahead.
Yeah.
They quit.
I don't want to welcome Jenny.
But Jenny is here.
She is our new director of CVB.
That's one of the two.
Would you go mouth that?
Yeah.
That's right.
Hi.
Thank you.
She's here.
Welcome to Jenny.
If you have met Jenny.
Sit right there.
Come up.
But she's started today.
So, welcome.
Oh, it works.
As you've heard, the ground breaking for the airport will be Friday.
So, I'm going to call.
I'm going to call.
Here at H.C. excited about this one.
Good.
Go indoors every night.
Yeah.
Okay.
For Kevin.
Yeah.
All right.
Go 16.
So, you may have your communication.
Yes, sir.
I have three to talk about.
So, the first is we've been a made aware that get in German.
That's followed the lawsuit.
Representing GRDA for a press manipulation.
From the military.
And I'd be something interesting.
Maybe I'd like to see the article or whatever.
Do you.
Interesting.
I mean, you know, we have 2.7 million.
No, we're from what are strong years.
There's been a few points out.
We're coming about to the.
We'll be able to be good.
Where.
We don't know how it's going to play out, but hopefully we can get some of that back.
So, we can have a power of the large sale.
Oh, I'm all about refunds.
Let me go.
The second thing is we've been made aware from GRDA that we are going to be getting our
are going to be getting a rating increase in the coming months.
Of course, one of them, so something that we will be presenting
have the rating analysis look at our rates.
Motion to deny.
And then I'm going to have that.
So I'm just going to make you wear the 4 to 5% increase for the next 4 to 5 years.
So I've got to be a 4.5% over the 30-time or every year every year every year every year every year every year
So just I just make it everybody where so I know we'll bring every like I said
I already announced this year to look at the rates to see because obviously we'll have to pass it on to the customers
You take that out for bid
Just to make it and that is not finalized yet. That is what they were talking about so that's about 20% of the degree
You have to put it on the 4 to 5 years
So just everybody be aware and it's all across the customer base
So I mean it's not just our customer class
But they'll be more to come on that as they have their board. That's actually pretty good
The last thing I have is that we
Staff and I resimitted three federal corporations request with Mark Wayne Lowell's office
So we
For the pool the trucker app and then safety center
So you know they reach out to us about
Appropriations put together
I mentioned information for them. So hopefully if those in
I federal bill to be funded to be really cool
Let me excited about that. Hopefully it's on the positive for that. That's all I have
17. The German
So move
Second